Well, look who's here. We are ready for
a free agency recap with Demarco Farmer
Maurice Jones. I'm JB Long back with a
fresh new edition of Between the Horns
as always, presented by your Southern
California Toyota dealers. Great to get
the band back together.
>> Colors. Yes, sir.
>> We've chatted behind the scenes, but we
haven't had a full sitdown since a lot
of good things went down. But how's your
spring been?
>> It's My spring's been awesome. got a
chance to get kind of get in the routine
a little bit. Uh loving all the trades.
Um loving all the moves the NFL's done
since the the the
the first day because there was some
stuff that happened before the first day
in that window that you know we don't we
probably not going to talk about
>> some great legal tampering this year.
>> Oh my gosh. I mean my guy Max Crosby
goes to Baltimore and then ends up back
in Vegas all while they've gotten
better. So it was it was good to see
that. Um but no, it's been awesome. my
I've been I've I've been enjoying my
time. How about you,
>> Ditto? Uh fit, recharge, ready to go. Uh
turned the page. Uh got over it. Took a
while after the Super Bowl. I'm sure we
all felt the same thing watching that
game like wow. Um imagine if um you you
got over the hump in Seattle. So, uh
recharge and then like you said, um just
going into free agency and to see how
many changes the teams the team has
made, uh to get better to chase that
Lombardi. So, yeah. uh energized,
ready to go. Good to see you guys and
let's get started.
>> Wasn't it you who kind of coined the
phrase like the window is now Shawn
McVeyy's window. Like we used to talk
about, oh, this gravitates around Aaron
Donald and then it became Matthew
Stafford's time. At some point last
year, you kind of shifted that for us
and you're like, "No, no, as long as the
coach and the GM are here, that's the
window."
>> Yeah. Let me I was going to attach an
addendum. I'm glad you did that. It is
the the Shawn McVey era, but it's being
fed by less need. And I think we all do
this in the NFL. Everyone looks for a
cookie cutter way to build a football
team. If you're trying to emulate or or
try to do what Les does, I don't think
you can because it's going to shift and
change and turn and and do all this type
of stuff. So just when you think they
don't pay their secondary, they do. Uh
they deal out one of the highest
salaries ever at that position. So uh it
is the McVey window, but it's definitely
being fed by less needed and company.
Yeah, I I think uh after you watched
last season, you're kind of like, "Okay,
we need to go get some guys to cover,
right?" And I went back and I was
watching some tape, there was a lot of
pressure from the Dline
>> and they would be like half a second
there. Like it'd be like a half a second
they'd get a sack or like something
would happen and the ball would just get
out and that that that's caused by the
secondary. We always hear the phrase the
front end has to match the back end,
right? And and vice versa. But you got
to slow down some of these receivers,
bro. you can't just have a running free
and the quarterback's able to hit his
fifth step and and and get the ball
where it needs to be. So, I think adding
McDuffy, adding all the corners, um
paying some of the guys you have in your
secondary is going to help that that
front that front end get the
quarterback.
>> Let's dig into some of that, how you
think it impacts Chris Schula's scheme
and a few other dimensions as we go
through this episode. But like biggest
picture possible, I wonder as former
players what your perspective is on
work now working for covering an
organization that sets a vision and
attacks the off season seemingly every
single January, February, March, and I
don't think that's universally true. You
look around the landscape and look, it's
not always perfect. Like that plan
doesn't always um come to fruition the
way that you had hoped. Some years
that's Devonte Adams and he leads the
National Football League in touchdown
receptions. Other years it's Allen
Robinson and it's an oops and le let's
try again, right? Um but I think you're
you're on the mark. We all know this
from this show and our audience. Like
the reason they're not getting fitted
from for rings right now, coverage and
kicking game.
>> And it seems like those were the two
intentions they set in February to get
right so that they're not desperate for
anything in the draft. I think the one
thing that you can't say they got lucky
on, but the one thing you can say the
Rams definitely have is the quarterback.
They have the right guy under center.
So, any decision you make that centers
or or puts him, you know, it's that's in
his orbit will make you better as a
football team. That's the one thing that
teams are trying to get right. So, um
Matthew Stafford is that guy. Um he is
special. He's a guy you want to feed
talent to definitely because he can make
stars and there's a lot of people I know
we're going to talk about the draft what
what you want to see out of this draft
coming up. There's some guys here that
are moving into their second year that
are going to make huge jumps because of
who's under center. So, uh there's a lot
more to come there. But yeah, it's I'm
with you on that. There there is a goal
uh to win. Maybe it started in Atlanta
when they lost to the Patriots and like
never again and then it was always pedal
to the metal and it always seems like
they've been chasing the Lombardi even
after they got one. Um, so that is cool.
Every team is trying to get to this
point, but I guess when you see it year
in and year out, it doesn't surprise you
anymore, but it just it surprises you
how the game has moved and how they stay
with it and stay on top of it and stay
ahead of it
>> even when it wasn't pedal to the floor.
Like let's say that 23 draft class,
right? Like 22 didn't go the way you
wanted to run it back.
>> Maybe your ambition wasn't to win the
Super Bowl that year, but they had a
very clear vision of what they needed to
do to get books right, to get
>> uh backups, projected starters on the
right track. And the reason they are
where they are now is because that
intention that offseason landed so
beautifully. Like that's now the class
that we're talking about handing some
extensions to this offseason. Well, I I
think Devonte Adams said it best and
it's it's about an ecosystem and he told
I he went on a a podcast or on a a forum
and was like there's no other place like
this because not every place wants to
win. Some people just want to make
money. Some people just want to have
good seasons. There's some teams that
we're in rebuild mode here. It's always
reload. We're trying to get better every
day, right? And there's different ways
to do that. But when you see your
organization going out getting a Dvonte
Adams in the offseason, making trades,
signing free agents, uh the way they've
drafted, uh the expectation they put on
guys, I was here um probably two weeks
after the Super Bowl with my son doing
the opening and uh Jared Vers is over
here doing curls in the weight room,
right? And I'm s I over here being dad
loving it, but at the same time like my
analyst has like who is that over there
working out, right? So you that that
mindset is here and it's all because it
starts at the top. You talk about that
window, right? It starts at the top. If
your GM is making certain moves and
being aggressive and like it's all about
the team and everything is then all of a
sudden it's going to permeate through it
through the building, right? Then the
coaches are going to feel that way,
right? The Rams continue to lose coaches
year after year after year and yet
they're still able to make stay where
they need to be. And so when you talk
about that window, when you talk about
these moves,
>> it all comes together. I guess at the is
what I'm trying to get to is like
everyone feels that, right? Like
everyone understands that. So when you
have your star player that comes in like
everyone needs to try to play for the
Rams.
>> You don't ever hear people say that
about like Buffalo or not everybody's
like, "Hey, everybody got to come to
Buffalo. We got Josh like no, it's not
that." And it's not necessarily about a
player. It's just what what they do
here. Just being in the building today
is just I saw Lesne walking and like
it's just a different energy here. Mhm.
>> There's a a caution not to get drunk off
free agency though, right? Because a lot
of times the dollars spent in free
agency don't always correlate to the
most wins in the fall.
>> And so it's an uneasy feeling to see
like offseason grades being handed out
already and and the Rams are at the top
of the class, right? But there's some
nuance to it in terms of they didn't
just break the bank and throw a lot of
money at at other teams top players.
Like the biggest move they made was
actually via a trade to get a
cornerstone piece. And then you look at
the rest of what they spent, whether
it's Watson or retaining Curl and
Higgby, you know, like spending for a
special teams linebacker. Like these are
not
luxury items, you know, like these are
not big ticket purchases that you made
trying to acquire other teams talent in
the way that we typically look at free
agency.
>> Well, I I never and agonized over a
question on this show ever uh than when
we were talking about did the Rams get
better with these offseason acquisitions
of these new corners, right? And it's
hard to answer that because the last
group they got better from one year to
the next and their last game was a game
away from the Super Bowl. So when you
get better, that means your improvement
would be what?
>> Super Bowl,
>> right? I mean, that is a tough thing to
carry for a group. But it is what it is.
That's how good this team is and that's
how filled out this team is. And when
you mentioned Cam Curl, so happy they
got that done. I think that means more
than anything that guy played every
freaking snap for you and he he played
hard-nosed football. He was an excellent
safety for you and he's rewarded. It
should be rewarded.
>> Big Rig is your guy. He's the heartbeat
of your football team.
>> So to identify that, keep that in the
group to keep that energy going. I
thought that was real important.
>> When he plays, it's just different and
it opens up so many different things in
the running game and the passing game.
What I will say is this. Um
the last time the Rams won the Super
Bowl, they had a big ticket corner. They
had a guy that could cover guys, right?
You were, you want to talk about what
Chris Schula is going to be able to do.
Um his blitz package, his his scheme, a
lot of what they did last year, I felt
like they had to run cover two to kind
of like try to disguise some things. Now
you can play press man pretty much
across the board if you want to. This is
what the Chiefs have done with their
different blitz packages. Uh I don't
think McDuffy is going to go to the
nickel slot and play in the slot. I
think that's going to be Quinton Lake,
but you still have guys that can cover
big-time guys and we can if we just go
up, you know, to the Bay Area, they just
signed two receivers.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Right. So, you're we're going to have to
have some guys that can lock up and
play.
>> Receiver and a giraffe.
>> Yeah.
>> But Watson But Watson has longer arm.
He's a longer guy. McDuffy can cover the
the the he could pretty much cover
everyone. Um and so you've given
yourself an opportunity to send pressure
and play press man behind. If we go back
to Seattle,
>> a guy that can travel,
>> right? If you go if you go back to
Seattle, um the the Seahawks had a third
and seven, right? You knew we talked
about on the broadcast if you show man,
they're just going to run crossing
routes. Well, McDuffy, he's smart enough
and he understands like I'm going to
take these things away. And I and I will
say this too because this it's about
relationships. The reason you were able
to go get McDuffy and spend the money
and do all that is because you have a
coacher who coached him in college who
recruited him out of high school here in
LA to Washington.
>> Go dogs. Woof. And then uh he is
comfortable enough if you have that
insight I can go I feel better about
spending that money than if I didn't
have that insight. So you know what he's
going to be able to bring to your
defense and as a defensive coordinator I
know I can be more aggressive in certain
situations.
>> Well I do know this about Spags from way
back in the day. He is a thinking man's
defensive coordinator. So if you can
play there and be good you can come here
and be good. There's easy carryover. You
fit. You know you know exact all it is
is getting reps with the guy you're out
there playing with. So you know what's
going on. What about the cost? Uh 29 and
three additional picks, including next
year's third rounder, and then making
him the highest paid player at his
position as it stands today.
>> When you watch it on tape, I mean,
>> what would you pay for a Super Bowl?
>> Anything you could pay.
>> It's not my money they're spending. I'm
good.
>> If that's if you believe he's if you
believe these are the guys to get you
where you need to get to, you spend the
you spend it. Yeah.
>> Period.
>> I mean, and that's going back to 23 and
24. This is why they aspired to this
moment where they would have both the
picks and the financial capital to make
another move like this if the
opportunity presented itself. Did they
know that the Chiefs were going to move
on from Trent McDuffy? Not necessarily.
But they put themselves in a position to
go one attack a perceived weakness, get
a caliber captain person on defense in
his prime and like you said, bring in
the coverage elements that can hopefully
get that fearsome 24 back to life.
>> Somebody has to cover JSN.
My guy is still open
>> and Shahed and my
I'm just I'm just I'm just going off of
JSN. No,
>> last the last time I I remember us
playing,
>> you know, I was depressed for like 4
days and then I went to the Super Bowl
and was even more depressed. Uh tried to
go to Brazil.
>> By the way, you called the Super Bowl
this year. I did. It was It was just in
Seattle two weeks before.
>> That's all I was.
>> Yeah. And I double back and I I just
called the the game after. I don't even
know if it was Super Bowl, but was
trying to go to Brazil. That got
cancelceled. So, I just been depressed.
So, like just understand JSN is still in
my mind running open at the scene.
>> It's not just him. I mean, when you
think about that Detroit game, um, St.
Brown had a day. Uh, but it wasn't those
guys. You expect those guys to get open.
It's like the Kendrick Bores that got
open that drove you nuts. Uh, who was
the guy in Arizona that kept getting
open? Is it Wilson? Wilson that just
Yeah. And I think even DeHop had a day
on you, but he's he's a vet. So, it's
just those things you could say, "Go get
him, sick him, travel with him, take him
away, and make this defense better." You
mentioned the pressures, man, and you
don't know how frustrating. Or you
might. You played defense at one point.
When you're third in the league in
pressures, you're getting there. You're
winning reps. You're you're freeing
yourself to get to the quarterback and
all you see is his hand come down
because the ball got out. That's going
to drive you crazy and you're wasting
your pass rush reps. This will help this
already good pass rush group be even
better. So, you'll have a chance to
threaten what Denver did. Denver's
calling card was they just mowed down
quarterbacks. You could have been that
exact same squad if you could have hold
up some of those guys just a little bit
longer. How about from a running back's
perspective, the pass pro chore of
dealing with a Rams defense that could
be sending corners, they could be
sending slot defenders, they could be
sending linebackers,
>> and you attack protections, right? And
to me, what I what I thought most
importantly about this, especially from
is like now have to worry about
chipping,
>> right? Because the Rams now can get to
you with four and play coverage with
seven. And we we tal spoke about this a
lot like they're not getting there.
They're not getting there. But when you
go and watch the tape, they were winning
like like DeMarco said, the ball was
just coming out quick. Now you're going
to have to hold the ball for half a
second longer and that that's going to
allow that sack to get to that pressure
to get there. Uh if you do blitz, you
know, I always I go back to Ernest Jones
in the Super Bowl when they were just
blitzing him on Joe Mixon. If you find a
guy that can rush like that has the
ability to rush, Lamb Man's more of a
ball hawk. I think Spade is just a big
time run defender. But if you they if
they can get their blitz package
together,
>> that's where you really take advantage
because that's how the Rams beat the
Bengals in the Super Bowl is blitz
blitzing Ernest Jones on Joe Mixon. he
wins a couple times. Now all of a sudden
you have to slide the protection now now
you have you can't have one-on-one with
him or Aaron uh Donald or any of the
other guys. So if you can if you can
start sending those blitzes um I think
it it'll just really put people in a
bind for sure.
>> Running past tackling as well. I mean,
stuffing the run on early downs and then
at the catch point being able to limit
yards after catch, I think are probably
some of the hidden ways where you're
going to get into some better downs and
distances with the defensive backs who
are going to be on the field in 26.
>> And you'll get off the ball, you'll get
off the field on third down with with
these DBs. When you watch when you watch
>> the sticks, you bring them down.
>> Oh, yeah. When you watch McDuffy, he is
he's never four yards. He's they're
never four or five yards away from the
DB. Like his catch, I'm right on top of
you. So, that's always a good thing. Uh
we know the leap that the Rams need to
make in the third phase, the the kicking
game. When you see them invest in a
special teams linebacker, in the highest
paid long snapper when they retain Meas,
like what's that signaling to you as as
an organization in terms of how much
that really is going to be a priority
this year?
>> Man, we've been doing this a while
together and just playing football our
whole lives are covering it. And I I I
don't think I've seen a special teams go
through that many how could I say uh
missteps in a year like where it's the
the kicking game. You're missing kicks,
you're getting kicks blocked, and then
you're having trouble uh in coverage and
then at towards the end of the year
you're having trouble with returns. It
just seemed like everything in the
middle of that you lost a coach.
>> Um but to still have a team go through
all that and finish one game shy of the
Super Bowl tells you how good this
football team is. So, um, we've all
cleaned up after messes before, cleaned
up after parties or if you've had a
flood in the basement. Uh, just by doing
a little bit, it looks like you did a
lot of cleaning. So, for the new guys,
Bubba Ventron coming in, if you get this
team just backed to zero, to where it's
credible, to where you can actually take
a breath when the long snapper takes the
field on any moment, you've done your
job. So, if you can settle that down uh
by having great snaps and shout out to
McUade who really came in and and kind
of saved the season last year, but if
that is perfect and your your battery is
good and your field goals, whether you
miss them or not, but the battery and
the operation is correct and your
fielding punts and you're covering
kicks, that will give the other two
units that are really good more
confidence in you. Uh because last year
there were games where the special teams
flat out cost you points,
>> which is the opposite of what teams are
supposed to do. I mean, that's what I
mean. Cost you points in a game, a tight
ball game that you ultimately lost. You
cannot have that. So just getting back
to zero would be a big benefit for this
football team. So uh I like Ventron as a
player. Yeah, he was all he was very
active. Kind of the same guy you just
signed at linebacker in Stewart. Same
dude when he gets on the field. Some
guys just have a knack for being where
the ball is. He's one of them. And
you've got a coach like that. So getting
back to zero, I think is just a that's a
big plus for this football team.
>> I I think it it's a big look in the
mirror to say we've kind of gotten away
with putting guys on special teams
because special teams players, it's a
it's a it's a certain type of guy,
right? It's a guy that reads and reacts.
It's a guy with speed and they have
different attribution offense and
defensive players. Mo most of the time
you have backup linebackers that if they
play it's like kind of like ah if they
play line like ah but on special teams
he he doesn't have to read he could just
run right and just be free. And I think
the Rams have gotten away with having a
lot of thinkers on special teams guys
that are probably better linebackers
than they are special teams players. And
so when you start adding to those guys
that can play special teams um it makes
it different. And the reason I say it's
like a Dalius Thomas, you know who that
is?
>> Oh yeah. He was he was a solid outside
linebacker for the Ravens,
>> but he was a demon on special teams. A
demon. And I'm talking about like six. I
mean, James Harrison for the Pittsburgh,
that's one of our our people. He was a
demon on special teams. He ended up
being he ended up becoming a good
linebacker at the towards the end of his
career. But the first bit of his career,
special teams, I remember going against
him. I was like, who is this monster out
here and this grown man grabbing on
people like this? But those you need
guys like that because it allows it it
it's a mindset. It's a different mindset
I would say. And so to see the Rams
invest in special teams the third phase
of the game which is the most important
phase of the game because it's like a
kicker. You don't know his name until he
misses a field goal. Right. Until the
game is over. And so
>> or until he makes one.
>> Yeah. Or until he makes one. But um it's
it's about really putting you can't
waste another day, another hour of
Matthew Stafford's career, right? by not
having the best special teams you can
have because again, like we've always
said it, you're literally a play away, a
play away from putting another ring on
and and you don't know what may happen.
And so when those things happen, you're
like, "Okay, we need to really go back
and re and I I wouldn't be surprised if
they do more of that."
>> I look at a team as like almost sliders
on an audio board, like offense,
defense, special teams. Your offense was
all the way at the top. Yeah. Can you
lead the league in scoring again? Yeah,
maybe. Is your quarterback going to win
MVP again? Maybe. Odds are against it,
right? But say you go one to five,
you're still in great shape there.
Defense, you can you can enter the top
10, if not the top five with the moves
you've made. Special teams, you got to
go from 30, whatever they were,
>> top 10
>> have to.
>> And and if you do,
>> that's going to impact winning. And it's
also not lost on me. I think you're kind
of touching on this a little bit,
improving the back end of your roster
with an eye towards special teams. This
is a franchise that used to draft on day
three, you know, the Nick Scots of the
world who were going to be dedicated
core special teamers. Next thing you
know, they're helping you win a Super
Bowl by by blowing up Debo S. But
>> but it started
>> he was he was a guy
>> a day one special teams. And you look at
round seven, they've got three picks at
the end of round seven.
>> Maybe that's fuel for a fire to move up
somewhere. Maybe that's just, hey, a
head start on college free agency. Maybe
those are luxury picks where it's like
we're gonna fill in Gunnar. We're gonna
fill like we're gonna have an eye
towards Bubba's first special teams
unit. I
>> I I would tell you it's hard when you
have and and no disrespect to our our
receivers. They do an awesome job and
they compete, but it's hard to have your
gunners as receivers.
>> Your gunners have to be able those
should be DBs. Those should be safeties,
corners, guys that can go down and make
plays that tackle for a living.
Receivers don't do that. Xavier Smith
doesn't tackle for a living, right? And
so you, as much as we love their
contribution into the special teams,
you're just asking guys to do something
that they normally don't do. Right.
Right. Like Xavier Smith has played
receiver his whole life. You know what I
mean? And then we get to the NFL, I want
you to tackle a guy. Now I want you to
go down here and tackle. Like he's done
an awesome job, but that's just not what
in his nature what he does.
>> Which, by the way, he's back.
>> And I'm glad he's back. He deserves to
be back.
>> No question.
>> He made a gruesome mistake at the end of
last season, and that hurt all of us. It
broke my heart for him.
>> Oh. But he did a great job last year and
he impacted the the receiver room as
well. So I'm glad that they signed him
back.
Who was the guy we we Rochelle? Remember
him?
>> Robert Rochelle.
>> He was a gunner that would go down and
like like those were like those are the
guys that you're looking for in that
third day guys like that long
>> safety safety corner linebacker guys.
Yeah. Yeah. Or you get tackle get one of
those receiver and name only guys
>> like you're only a receiver because
that's where we put you but your job is
to go cover. Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. 88 as a gunner, but that makes
every time.
>> We had a guy like that in Jacksonville.
He played he played everything. They
tried to put him at linebacker, running
back, safety. Bro, you're just playing
special teams.
>> Right. Right.
>> And you're the happiest for him when he
scores, right? Cuz he's not that guy.
>> If you find the next Matthew Slater in
this draft class, let us know.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's another one I was going to I was
going to I just tried to stay away from
my my guy, but we need one of those for
sure.
>> Uh you mentioned the coaching staff
turnover year over year. It's it's a
problem the Rams have really become
adept at solving for. Um, among the news
items, Nate Sheiel House replacing
Michael Lafleur, now the head coach um
of the Arizona Cardinals. Uh, Jimmy Lake
was the the connection to McDuffy that
you touched on, now the pass game
coordinator and defensive back coach.
Cliff Kingsbury, we haven't talked
about. What' you make of that move? Help
your boy out. Come on over here. Let's
let's get together. Let's put some ideas
together. But, uh, you know, this is,
uh, the Rams rehabilitation for coaches
facility as well. come over here, get
rehabbed up. We'll get you back on
track. We'll let you go do your thing
wherever you want to go next.
>> Robert Woods on the coaching staff that
me too.
>> Love it.
>> Yes.
>> Brian Allen, too.
>> Love it.
>> Yeah.
>> Lobby trees and yards.
>> I What I love about that is it's so
different here. Again, I keep talking
about the ecosystem here.
>> How many former players, you know, got
got a chance to get on with the team
that they
>> the same team?
>> Not many.
>> It doesn't happen that way. And for Sean
to give a guy, oh, you want you don't
know what you you're it's done. Like,
and I'll tell you, I know DeMarco said
the same thing. Transitioning from
football to the real world is crazy
>> cuz you realize there's 24 hours in a
day.
>> Yeah.
>> Like majority of my days, 16 of those
were go was football, eight was sleep
pretty much. Like you get a little bit
of family here and there, but majority
of time you're working on your craft.
You're thinking about your game. When
you retire, you don't have to think
about it. It's 24 hours in the day,
>> right? And so you're like, "What am I
going to do? I have nothing to do. I
have no schedule. I have nothing going
on. And for Shawn to recognize that and
say, "Here, you want to coach? You have
an interest in coaching. I don't know
how that conversation happened. If you
want to here, come on. We'll bring you
on here. Keep you. You're right here at
home. You live right here. You could
help us get our guys better. You brought
the physicality to our The reason our
receivers blocked the way they are
because of you, right? We want that all
to come this way." I mean, it's full
circle and it's a special moment. But
like I said, there's not many teams like
that uh that do that. Not many.
>> Yeah. you use the word gives and I know
you didn't mean it this way, but I think
Sean was very careful to say these are
earned opportunities and and these guys
come in with their eyes wide open in
terms of that transition from playing to
coaching in terms of what it takes uh to
deliver at the standard that the Rams
have set.
>> What's the first thing you think of when
you say Robert Woods? What's the first
thing that comes to mind?
>> The touchdown against the Texans.
>> I was going to say post the post.
>> The one in New York wasn't bad either.
>> 3033 to the house.
>> To the house to the house. I mean, how
many times or how many times he leading
down Cooper Cup as he breaks a tackle,
he blocks the
>> His name and Sharpie on Witworth's
t-shirt underneath his pads and the
embrace when the confetti's fallen.
>> See, welcome. Yes. Yes, sir.
>> Those are like institutional core
memories. That's not bad to have in the
building.
>> This is what I love about coaching. Um,
not only can he tell you, he can show
you.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> He can absolutely show you what he needs
from you and then compete with you at
the same time. as a player too. The
other thing is you could put on tape of
him doing showing exactly. Yeah. Like he
did this
>> right now. He's here to coach you to
help you do that. And
>> one other thing on Cliff, like as more
and more of this tree permeates the
league,
>> you got to stay ahead in terms of the
evolution and I don't know what
ingredient he's going to be, but I like
the fact that even when you bring your
MVP quarterback back and two of his
favorite targets and his entire tight
end room, maybe there's something there.
Maybe it's scheme. Maybe it's
>> screen game,
>> what whatever the the next layer is
that's going to differentiate the 26
Rams from the 25 so that
uh defensive coordinators around the
league who are spending all of these
days and months trying to figure out how
to stop the best offense in the National
Football League might have a counter
punch ready to go.
>> Not might, will have a counter ready to
go. The one thing I love about Cliff
Kingbury, his offense that he ran, they
they use the heck out of screens. They
were they will screen you to death. They
will throw a bubble screen, a wide
receiver screen, a running back screen,
a tight end screen,
>> cuz it to in his mind, I haven't spoken
to him, but it looks like he counts it
as a running game,
>> right? Like, makes sense. It's like, oh,
this is a run play for us.
>> It's a way to get the ball in the
perimeter and get the ball outside. And
who's your biggest running your biggest
ball carrier? Imagine Puka catching five
more screens in a game.
>> Yeah, I can imagine that. Yeah,
>> it's not going to be Stafford RPO, so
well,
>> it could be.
>> We were going to jump to draft next, but
I kind of feel like uh let's stay in the
pipeline and just talk NFC West real
quick and get reaction to how the
competition has changed.
>> All right.
>> Uh, pick a team. Where do you want to
start? Seahawks, Niners, this real
quick. It's an arms race.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> It's an arms race now
>> in this division. Oh my gosh.
>> Yeah.
>> I think maybe the three best teams in
the NFC, like you take the top three and
you plug them into any AFC division and
I think they're the favorite in the NFC,
right?
>> Oh, yes, for sure.
>> Okay. Um, the Seahawks coming off a
Super Bowl
>> and losing some pieces I think did as
well as they could. Why don't we start
there?
>> Well, I I don't know who's their runner
going to be.
>> I would have Char.
Yeah, he's he late drafting. I could see
that
>> drafting a guy, going after it. But I
mean, look, you know, when you win a
Super Bowl, you lose half your football
team and everybody has their hand,
>> but their roster so good and so young,
they didn't they didn't have to make the
do you pay do you pay your guys for
performance on task already?
>> They did a pretty good job of keeping
that group together. So, yeah. Um,
Seattle is going to be everything they
were this past season.
>> Maybe maybe even better.
>> I don't know. And I'll say this, you
lost a lot, right?
We've never seen Seattle lose a coach
and have to bounce back and multiple
coaches at that, right? And that's the
one thing I will say they and then there
was Yeah. So, if you lose your OC, he
took half his staff with him.
>> You brought the guy from the ners up. We
don't know how he is calling plays,
right? The O line coach Dennison did an
amazing job.
>> Amazing job with that. How is that going
to fair now with that coach not being
there? Right. He did a great It was two
years he was there and or no, one year,
right? He was one year he was there and
like that offensive line looked
completely different. So that to me is
is they they they did a great job of
keeping things, but they lost a lot.
>> And then you don't know you don't know
who your running back's going to be.
That that team was based off of their
running game.
>> See if they continue to draft as well as
they have in recent years. The Niners
are the one that bother that bother me.
>> Oh, no question. I mean, they were
already a team that was one home win
away in week 18 from being the one seed.
Right now, they get a third place
schedule.
>> Both Bosa and Warner back.
>> They get Mike Evans on on one and 15
basically. That's annoying. Um Christian
Kirk, Dre Green Law. We'll see. The Osa
Diggiza one really bothers me.
>> Good, isn't he? Yeah, that's a problem
>> for a for a third. Okay. So,
>> you get you get interior pass rush.
>> Yeah.
>> For a third for a team that's already a
Super Bowl ready.
>> You thought should be more or less?
>> Anybody? I mean, could anybody in the
AFC have paid that, please?
>> Maybe. I mean, here's the thing. Like,
with with Puna's arrival here and how
much he changed the defense. Not going
to go that far, but he's another tree
stump in the middle of the football
field that you got to deal with, that
you got to dig out. He's a problem. And
he's a dude that also can straighten out
and get after you
>> for a defense that had to get more stout
right up the spine. They put him in,
they get Fred back and they look
different.
>> Yeah, I I didn't even Dre Green law is
going to be a problem. I don't regards
whatever him in that system, listening
to him talk about Denver and how it was
there and how complicated the defense
was and we talked about think all this
thinking you you just
>> and an extra year away from a bad
injury. You just run you just run and
hit over there. And then you got the
double agent Raheem Morris who go
doubles back,
>> right? So you you there there that's
>> more than the players. I I've always
said this and I and I make sure I'll say
it again. I hate when we play former
Rams coaches. I hate it
>> because you have so much information on
how the Rams practice, what Shawn likes
to do in certain situations,
>> what he might be thinking.
>> What he might be thinking, all these
things like that to me, I just hate
that. But that's why and I I tied it
into Cliff Kingsbury. That's part of it.
That's one component of it. But you look
at the mid-season pivot the Rams made to
the two and three tight end sets, like
that's a better example of, hey, the
more Raheem Morrises that are out there,
the more that are very familiar with
your your pre-nap operation, your
tendencies, your down distances. So the
self scouting becomes, I think, one of
the biggest tasks
>> of any Rams off season because
>> you've now got nine years of amazing
sample size with multiple quarterbacks,
multiple and some of it's personnel
driven.
>> Like the biggest thing about getting
Devonte Adams was, yeah, third down and
unlocking the red zone, but it allowed
you to be a completely different offense
in some of those money downs and
distances than you had been previously
because of your personnel. and we'll get
to it in a second, but maybe there's an
opportunity to do that again this off
seasonason.
>> Yeah, I I just dislike Raheem Morris
going to the M. Love Rahee Morris. Great
guy, but it's just this gives me the
Panther vibes again. It's just like it's
like what are we doing? Why why like you
could just came back home and kicked it.
What are we doing? I I know this wasn't
directly Raheem's doing, but the way
that last April went, I know that loss
in Atlanta was painful, but to have
Terrence Ferguson and an extra first
round pick that parlayed into Trent
McDuffy, we're all good with Raheem
Morris. Always you're solid with that.
Good point. All right, I'll take it.
>> He can continue to give us all the fits
he wants on Sundays. Great point.
>> I I will say I think Mike Evans is going
to be a problem.
>> Oh, yes.
>> There's going to be an issue. Um
>> what a monster on inbreaking routes.
Kyle Kyle Shannon doesn't know know what
to do with that. I just think in the red
zone they're just going to throw fades
to them. I think that's is going to be
an issue. And then defensively, yeah,
interior interior pass rush.
>> There's another one.
>> It's and it's like so who what are we
doing? Who are we like who you going to
double team in this situation? You got
Bosa like
>> is it's going to be that's going to be a
>> I'm hoping at this point you don't have
to, but you're going to have to. Yeah.
And the Cardinals are probably gonna
have a new starting quarterback in 2027.
Yes. Yes.
>> Okay. All right. Um,
>> we'll go light on the draft because
we'll be back for plenty of Between the
Horns pre-draft content here, but let me
just ask this
>> big picture.
>> I thought we'd see the end of the Kyler
Murray era. I guess I did,
but it's weird. It's like, remember when
it started and now it's going to change
again?
>> I I thought he would be perfect in this
system. Uh uh.
>> Oh my gosh. I If your OC goes to
Arizona, to me, bootlegs, run game with
Kyler.
>> See, he knows. I keep telling people
Kyler is scary.
>> Yeah. Scary little guy. Yeah.
>> Happy he's out of here, but
>> me. Me, too.
>> Ecstatic for he's gone. I don't see a
Kyler coming in this draft anytime soon.
>> Do the Rams pick at 13?
>> Yes.
>> You think they end up picking at 13?
>> Yes. I'm not confident.
>> Thursday night of the NFL draft. You
think the most likely scenario is they
take the 13th
>> pick? To be I think it you know what
there may be some enticing players
around that 13th pick that I that I
think you might want to get in on.
>> Like what? Like what player? What?
>> Maybe receiver. Yeah, I it's funny you
say that because we talked about this
and before
I didn't think receiver would be a
possibility, but after seeing kind of
what you did in you've done in free
agency, um receiver is definitely like
high up on the list
>> as someone
>> let's say pass catcher.
>> Pass catcher. Okay, I see.
>> You think you think 13 is uh is your
>> I think I think Arizona I think Arizona
State's there and that that may be an
issue, right? But I'm saying, okay, you
got seven to here's where I'm there's my
calculus. You got seven total picks. I
think of your 53man roster, maybe 45,
46, 47 helmets are pretty much
>> locked in.
>> I think two or three more of those have
to be offensive linemen that you need
names for between now and kickoff. Maybe
a third quarterback. All that to say,
you have more picks than helmets
available, I think. So, if you wanted to
continue to go up and be aggressive, we
know they've tried in previous drafts.
If there's a future allp pro within
reach, could you go above 13?
>> Sure.
>> I think so, too. That being said, having
addressed just about every on paper
need, could you sit and pick at 13 and
have your choice of a lot of really good
options? Yes. So many that you might try
and recoup some of that draft capital
that you've already used?
>> Like, is the difference between picking
at 13 or 16 or 17 or 18 that that
different? I don't know.
I have to I have to dive back into this
college thing. I I'll let you picking
up.
>> Well, so here's you drop down 10 spots.
That's my other big thought. Do you go
>> lineman or?
>> So, to the extent that the Rams still
have air quote needs, I would probably
list offensive line depth with has to
have starting upside of course, pass
catchers and corners. I would like if if
your favorite corner fell to 13 or even
say 11 or 12, I'd be fine with that. or
trading back and you still get a great
corner at 18 1920. I'd be great with
that. But I think in those ranges, you
might be able to find your next Rob
Havenstein.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> You might be able to find
a pass catcher that will help you back
fill some of the ones that you're going
to lose or have to pay real soon. Yeah,
I would I'm just thinking about it's
hard for me to look in the I I'm
thinking about next year like
the Niners twice, Seattle twice. Those
are going to be problems. How do we win
those games?
>> What can help you now?
>> Yeah. What can help me today? Like
>> to me, it's having a third receiver that
is going to be like, okay, when this guy
comes in, maybe Devonte takes a rest.
This guy comes and now it's him and
Puka. Who How are you going to handle
this? But can I I I know you're
thinking, but I would argue that a
backup offensive lineman who has first
year starting potential is an is a
similar answer to that question because
the Rams lost both offensive tackles at
one point last season. Thank goodness
Warren McClennon was there waiting
otherwise you would have been in a world
of hurt and the one game where you
didn't have Aller Jackson.
>> Yeah.
>> And that almost cost you a chance to
chase a championship too,
>> right? So, if you can fi with Warren
entering a contract year, if you can
find again a tackle of the future or a
tackle who has guard and tackle backup
flex, I think that is an asset that
keeps you on track to maximize
Stafford's window.
>> I agree with that, too. I'll never be
upset with drafting big men.
>> No, it's it's either way, either
protecting him or giving him somebody to
throw to. Uh but it's all I'm I'm with
you. Uh you definitely need to restock,
especially at tackle. um it's time to
fill out that a little bit more just to
protect yourself there. But I mean like
if you've got one of these talented pass
catchers regardless of position staring
you in the face, it would be hard to say
no. Or if you have a top flight pass
rusher would be more
>> for me to say no.
>> What what have the most recent champions
taught us about the current NFL? Eagles
and Seahawk. You can never have enough
pass rushers
>> ever. They got guys. there's another guy
that's staring you in the face that gets
there in a hurry that slips and he's
there. I could see that too and it all
makes you better because remember what
you have in your secondary now.
>> Let let me ask you about your your
receiver pass catcher appetite of which
I have a similar one. Does the fact that
the Rams have been able to produce all
pros, triple crown winners, Super Bowl
MVPs
>> like fifth, third round
>> from from later days dissuade you at all
from taking a first round?
>> Yeah, cuz I want to see what you do with
that. What do you do with that? What do
you do with that?
>> Exactly.
>> It's like it's like, "Hey, I've seen you
cook with like like a fork and a knife.
Like, let me get you some real utensils
and see what you can make. Maybe maybe
we maybe we may make a chain."
>> Yeah. Here's this electric knife. Let's
see what we do with that.
>> Exactly. Yeah. I I I I want to see what
they do with a like a top-notch
like ready to go guy.
>> Okay. Okay. Well, next time we talk, I
want some conviction from you about whe
whether there is someone of that
caliber.
>> I will let you I'm going to get a phone.
I'm going to go on the phone after this.
Let you know.
>> All right. Um do want to close this show
with some goodbyes. We're not going yet,
but you know, I've mentioned his name
here a couple of times. Rob Havenstein.
I want to talk a bit about D will Kobe
Durant 22 out. Some of the other Rams
that we've really enjoyed being around
have won a lot of games here in Los
Angeles that I think deserve a little
carve out. Um let's start with Rob
Havenstein. Mhm.
>> I mean, there were a couple years that I
thought were Pro Bowl worthy. Never got
the recognition outside of this facility
that he deserved. But again, to put this
in perspective, if you could find the
next Rob Havenstein
somewhere this April, that would be a
massive win in terms of your
organizational stability.
>> I I just thought I mean, came over with
the team from St. Louis and has been a
staple, right? There's been times where
he's been banged up, but the leadership
that he's shown, uh, you know, sometimes
leadership is serving. When Andrew
Witworth came, he kind of took a back
step and let Witworth be the leader and
kind of went that way. And then when he
was gone, step back into that role. And
to me, that was that's huge. Um, and
then on top of the play, he was just a
road grader. He was moving guys left and
right and then still had the ability to
hold guys off. Uh I mean what the reason
the Rams won the Super Bowl was partly
because of what he was able to do uh
against the the Tampa Bay Buccaneers and
uh what no is it the Bucks? Who do he
played? It was the Bucks, right? I want
to say because uh Witworth got banged up
in the Bucks and
>> but anyways
he he showed up huge in big moments. So
congrats to him. Enjoy retirement. It's
worth it.
>> Yeah, you know, just watching him grow
and um he's another offensive lineman
from Planet Wookie. the dude is huge and
to see him change his body type I guess
three times over came in big Wisconsin
dude then he narrowed down got lean and
then he kind of filled out um into that
Witworth type you he just picked up as
you know picked up more and more
experience as he went along and just
made himself into a great player was
always a good player made himself into a
great player just to see him never break
character he's tough as nails and then
to like you say quietly assume that
leadership role um and and just be like
the beacon of what the O line stands for
and this is how we do things and passed
it on to the next group. So, I thought
that was awesome. Um, yeah, he's going
to be missed. Uh, just seeing Big Rob,
he was if I was the head coach, he'd be
the first or second guy I'd have get off
the bus because of how big he is. Yeah.
>> And make sure you take your shirt off
the same way. Yeah. Big dude.
>> When you combine storyline, narrative
arc, and performance, Darius Williams is
one of my favorite Rams during our time
together. like I have just always
enjoyed watching him play and knowing
how he got to the National Football
League and then two stints with the Rams
I think makes the story that much
richer. I just go back to Seattle during
co
>> the pick six
>> the pick six like changed everything and
and there's multiple times that he's
made plays in the game uh a late PBU or
interception that kind of changed the
game against the the ners right
overthrow by Pury he's right there to
pick the ball off he was always where he
was supposed to be and you could trust
that he was going to be where he needed
to be and so uh then he went to
Jacksonville which was awesome a
Jacksonville kid I got a chance to speak
with him so But, you know, it's it's
always tough to see the good ones go. He
was a guy that I thought came and gave
Rams some quality quality reps uh in
some big moments.
>> Speaking of the Jacksonville twist,
the the dots don't completely connect,
but let's not let the truth get in the
way of a good story because in Rams
lore, D will going to Jacksonville was
always part of the calculus that helped
them get Puka Nakua, right? like that
comp formula, D will's departure, being
willing,
>> wow,
>> to to separate from those incredible
years, one of which they led the league
in in defense, right? Him going to
Jacksonville gave them the capital that
eventually led to drafting Pukanua and
then they got D will back. So
>> weird.
>> Um Kobe Durant only gets a one-year deal
with the Cowboys. Um but a half a dozen
picks last year was special in the
playoffs. The Land Shark.
>> Listen, man. Good luck, man. Yeah,
>> he just
If you're Dallas, you guys, uh, I don't
know if you play Seattle or not. If you
do, he's going to pick off Sam Darnold.
That's his ass. He's going to be right
where he needs to be, right? Like, like
Sam is going to throw him the ball. And
so, uh, but you what I loved about Kobe
Durant was it was like he's not supposed
to be where where that ball is. And for
whatever reason, he's right there. The
pick against Chicago, uh, the first one,
he's not there's no one supposed to be
there on that overthrow. He's right
there. Right. And so it's just I mean he
did an awesome job. Again, another guy
that just showed up.
>> Yeah.
>> I remember being on the I remember
missing the Denver game cuz I got stuck
in uh
over in on the East Coast with the ice
storm and the pick six he had against
Denver to kind of send them on their way
um here at Sofi. I forget what year it
was, but it was
>> Did you miss the Christmas game?
>> I missed the Christmas game because I
did I had to do NFL Network in
Pittsburgh and I got stuck. Yeah. So, I
was on the plane watching and he uh does
his thing. So, always always around the
ball.
>> Yeah. A lot of Marcus Peters in there,
right? You kind of show up where the
ball is. That's just just instincts. Uh
but just real quick about D will. It's
like we've all taught our kids to ride
bikes and I remember when they put him
out there for the first time like, uh,
can this dude actually do it? Yeah, that
was pretty good. Let's see it again. You
know what? He's actually pretty damn
good. He became a starter. Actually,
he's the best guy we got in the
secondary. Yeah. And then you hate to
see him leave. And then when he came
back, he brought nothing but leadership
to the secondary. But, uh, Durant too,
good luck in Dallas. Um, I thought he's
I think there's the the best is yet to
come for him with corners and certain
guys in in football. Um, like a Kell
Witherspoon just for a half second. You
see what he looked like when the light
came on. He he was different. Same with
Kobe Durant. I think there's nothing you
can throw throw at him that he doesn't
know now. So, all he can and do is
improve depending on the team he's on.
So, good luck there. But, uh, with that
being said, you definitely upgraded that
position. So, as long as you work as
hard as the same guys that came before
you, because that's the one thing about
that secondary group, they worked hard.
They brought it every single game. Uh,
if you give them more talent and they
work just as hard, then the result
should be that much better. But, uh,
great example by D will, great example
by Rob Havenstein. I mean, they they
left a great legacy. All right, we'll
let you get back to your brackets and
your
>> Whoa, whoa, we didn't talk about 22
Atwell, Mr. Always Open. I'm sad to see
him go.
>> I really am. JB, how many times did he
come in? We all said
>> I'm out of the choir over here. You go.
>> I don't know. People understand how hard
it is. I I did it one time in my career
and I was like, that's kind of why I
retired. We were playing in Denver. I
was with the Raiders. I didn't play all
game. They're like, go in there in the
fourth quarter and play. And I was like,
bro, these this these legs don't work
like that. like I got to and I went out
there and I got destroyed. To see him
come off the to come off the bench in
the divisional game against the Eagles
and catch like a 20 yard comeback and
just continue to show up and just little
moments here or there without
>> getting the the all the reps.
>> That that's special. And so you're going
to Miami where you're going to get the
chance to be the guy.
>> They let they're trading everybody. It's
a it's a it's a a garage sale in Miami.
So you get a chance to go and be a guy
that's going to be exciting to see. It
kind of reminds me of where I started
whereby I love the intention that this
organization sets every offseason and
the way they go after it. It doesn't
always work out perfectly. I remember
that off season the intention was to get
faster it felt like. Right. So it wasn't
just 2 in the draft but it was Deshawn
Jackson too, right?
>> And look, did that go swimmingly? Not
always, but like
>> they had they had cast a vision for what
they needed to do that off season. and
did they ever go after it again here at
a different position group on a
different side of the ball. You can see
what they meant to do in February and
March. And I'm not saying it's mission
accomplished, but they executed.
>> Good start.
>> They executed. And now it's up to the
players and coaches to make it right.
>> All right. What's on the horizon?
>> Getting Stafford sorted out. Figuring
out who Stafford's backup's going to be
>> and then maybe some uh some extensions
for that class of 2023 led by Puka
Nakua.
>> There's a lot of money going to be out
there. Can't wait to see it.
>> He earned it.
>> No question.
>> He earned it. Yes, sir.
>> Fun time of fun time of life, I'm sure.
Right. Having gone through it as a
>> Oh, man. What?
>> I remember like it was yesterday.
>> Um, all right. We'll pause there. Good
to knock some rust off. Good to get
Demarco Far and MJD back together. We
will, of course, have pre-draft coverage
coming. Man, it's
>> coming around.
>> Rapidly approaching.
>> Yes.
>> I'm terrified.
>> Of what? All it's new.
>> Oh,
>> come on.
>> Listen, I want to go back to December
where things were just starting to, you
know, get things going and we we knew
there was there. And
>> January, those that was good times.
>> Uh, have a great March Madness. Enjoy
your uh, NCAA tournament watching and
all the other things you're going to do
this weekend for MJD and Demarco Far.
I'm JB Long. Talk to you soon on Between
the Horns presented by your Southern
California Toyota dealers.